Um well hopefully the same but yeah I
mean every time you I mean you approach
everything the same and you want to
really uncover every stone and and do
all the work on all the different
possibilities whether that's you know
you stay in pick you trade back you
trade up and you want to be sure you
have all your bases covered because you
don't know what's going to happen on
draft day if a team you know wants to
trade up from 27 you have to be ready
for that like who's going to be there at
27 is that worth it, you know, or do you
want to trade back, you know, not as far
or all those things. So, every process
is is very similar. We want to make sure
you cover all your bases, know everybody
in the draft, not just the guys that are
in the top seven or whatever, because
you never know what's going to happen.
So, uh, but we're working really hard.
Our our college staff's been grinding
since it's really August and in the
summer. So, we have a great, uh, kind of
setup right now and we're we're just
getting into that after we get into free
agency, really digging into the draft,
but those guys have been doing work all
year, so we'll be ready to go.
evaluating that position.
>> Yeah, I think I mean uh answer the first
question, you know, evaluating the edge.
Um just guys that you know fit your
scheme and your profile and we have new
scheme this year with with Donte and so
but I think a lot of that stuff carries
over. If you're a really good pass
rusher, you're always going to um you're
going to, you know, you like pass rush
is going to weigh more than than run
defense, especially the way this league
is. But I mean, ideally, you want Miles
Garrett, you know, that's that's who you
want, but there's only one of those guys
walking on the face of the earth. So,
but a lot of those same traits, right?
And um you know, long, fast, explosive,
can turn the corner, can finish, all
those things. Um, in terms of guys with
shorter arms, um, and there's a few in
this draft that are really, really good
players, it's, you know, arm length is,
I mean, I can go into to days on this
arm length thing because every time you
measure somebody's arm, it could be 30,
31, 32, 33, just depending on who
measures it. So, um, you get a pretty
good idea of how long their arms are
with that. But you really how how well
they play with whatever length they
have. Some guys have shorter arms that
play with great length and extension all
the time. Some guys have really long
arms that don't use that their length as
well. So, uh, you know, it's great to
have that length, but it's also how they
use it and and how how it comes out on
the tape. And so, some guys can excel
with shorter arms by doing things
differently, but you know, ideally, you
always want to have air on the side of a
longer person. Yeah.
going into their second.
>> Um, yeah. I mean, I think it's hard, but
I think you uh that's just this league,
you know, and and we had what, 10 head
coaching changes, so there's just always
going to be turnover and volatility just
based on the way this league is is built
and run. And and a lot of teams have
done really well. Like you look at the
Patriots, they got to the Super Bowl
this year with with a new coordinator,
albeit a really experienced and good
one. Um, so it just matters, you know,
how quickly you can implement that. And
so, you know, when you do that, what's
your plan? Like how how are you building
that for success with the players that
you have, you know, starting as soon as
you hire them? How are they building the
installs? How are they teaching it? And
how quickly can the players learn and
adapt and and excel in it? So, yeah,
sure. It's hard. It really is. But um
you know that's that's our jobs.
when you're dealing with a quarterback
still.
>> Yeah, I think you know with Jaden, you
know, all of our decisions are really in
in consideration of him and this one uh
especially with with keeping David Blau
and and their history for the last two
years of working together. So that that
helped a lot, you know, and that that
gives us a lot of confidence. They have
an incredible working relationship and
and David's an incredible coach. So that
that will help speed up the process for
sure where you don't have the getting to
know kind of trust building factor that
trust is already built. So that'll
really help us moving forward. But um
you know I think that's everything you
know we're going to be doing is is going
to be with Jaden in mind.
>> Expectations you guys are going to walk.
>> No, we haven't made it a final decision
there. There's a lot of things that go
to go into that and you know we have
we'll still have a few more
conversations Ben but um you know until
then yeah he's still on our team.
Um yeah, coaching staff question like I
don't want to get too deep into that but
you know that that's the plan is to
absorb that you know somehow some way uh
whether it's internally or externally
but um you know we've we've had some
conversations about that but uh you know
really what we want to do is is make
sure we surround David Blau with as many
uh people that can help him as possible
to ensure he has the every chance of
success. So yeah, we'll do that.
>> Brown gyms and those guys being such
>> Yeah, it it that is a good question and
I think um you know I think obviously
it's not orthodox for a college director
to leave at this time. Um, so we will
have our work to do. But, um, I think in
terms of Tim, you know, I really, you
know, it's that was a personal thing for
me too. When I was a college director at
Denver, uh, I got asked to go to the
49ers, which was my hometown team. And,
and great man by the name of John Elway,
uh, allowed me to do that. And so, I
wanted to pay that forward. And I think
Tim has earned that, more than earned
that really with his 24 years of service
to us. And so, um, you know, that that
certainly is not going to be easy, but I
really have a lot of confidence in our
staff to to make up, uh, for the next
few months at least to to pick up the
slack.
>> Yeah. So that that's a really good
question, John. And and um I think you
know it's going to be a little bit
different in terms of the players we're
looking at and looking for and and what
we're looking for in those players. Um
we a couple weeks ago when after we
hired Donte and both him and David did
an incredible job for us. Uh they
presented to the whole football staff,
you know, their vision for offense and
defense. So David went first and talked
about offense, our vision, our scheme,
and then got into the particular players
and what we're looking for in those
particular players. And they painted a
great picture for us. And Donte did the
same. And you know, it was really super
impressive. First of all, those guys are
both really, really smart and really,
you know, really excited about them, but
Dante did a great job of painting the
picture of what we're looking at in this
and and how the front's multiple. So it
doesn't have to be, you know, it's not
just super specific, but if a guy can do
multiple things, then um you know, that
the versatility is is probably more of a
premium now. But um in terms of that,
they've done an incredible job painting
the picture for us and giving an idea of
what we need to go do to help help them
find those players. So, and then now
that's our job to to go find them.
>> Yeah. How important is it to get that
done before?
>> Um, you know, I don't want to put a
timeline on it, JP. Um, but it is really
important for us, you know, and and
we've been having talks and we've been
having good and productive talks with
Laramie and his team. And um, you know,
we're as motivated as ever to to get
that done, but I don't I don't want to
put a timeline on it. Obviously, I don't
think either side wants to drag it on,
but I don't think the the league year is
is anything that's going to be a
deadline of sorts.
Well, Jennifer,
>> Brandon Aayuk is a player on another
team under contract, so I can't comment
on that. Um,
uh, second chances. Yeah, I think uh I
think everybody on on earth deserves a
second chance. And so, uh, with Kinlaw,
I mean, that that was an interesting
one. Kinlaw earned his second chance and
really um, you know, he he earned every
every single bit of it. And so, um, I
wouldn't I wouldn't kind of call his a
second chance, so to speak. I think
because I had the familiarity with him
and and understanding the type of person
and player and and competitor he is,
that that helped uh factor into that
decision. But I think he earned every
single bit of that by the way he came
back from his injuries and everything to
be a really really good player. So, uh,
in terms of Brandon, love the person,
but don't can't really comment on the
player. players who are under contract.
So a couple years ago probably the
biggest question at the combine just
amazing style of play.
>> Yeah, I think there's um you know some
of these injuries right for anybody are
freak injuries and things that would
happen to anybody. Uh but Jane Jane's
well aware of um you know just being
able to protect himself and
understanding the importance of that and
being available and and you know we've
talked about this a lot but he's he
certainly uh understands that and um but
it's not just on Jaden. It's on all of
us. It's on you know our our scouting
staff to find the receivers and the and
the linemen and the running backs to
support him so he doesn't have to do it
all himself. It's on the coaches you
know with with the way they coach him
and what the call the plays we call and
the scheme and everything like that. So,
it's a team effort, but certainly it is
a premium to to keep him healthy for
sure
>> to him. Um, you know, I couldn't put a I
mean, we we talk about it a lot, but
like I don't know if there's a a number
on it.
Yeah, Larry's under contract for this
next year. So, um, yeah, so he's got one
more year on his contract. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Andrew, um, one, I can't say
enough good things about him, the person
and the player. Uh he's he's uh what we
would call a true commander in terms of
his work ethic, his competitiveness. Uh
he's an elite teammate. Um and he's
super versatile. Like I mean he can line
up at four spots. So he's super
valuable. I think he's, you know, he's
still got enough talent to start and um,
you know, so he was s he was a priority
for us to to bring back, you know, and
there there's a there's a number of
those guys, but Andrew was at or near
the top of that and and we're thrilled
to have him back and and uh, you know, I
just can't say enough good things about
him and and uh, the more of the guys
like that you have, the better your
team's going to be.
>> Pardon me.
>> Did you learn more about Andrew this
year in terms of
Yeah, I think um you learned a lot about
him this year and just uh you know the
type of human being he is like we had a
contract that that we had to restructure
last year and the way he responded to
that um uh is better than than I could
ever imagine myself responding to like
he is a uh an outstanding person you
know a team first person and um so that
was the first part but just being around
him for another year as a human being
and understanding what he means to that
room and to the offense in general. Um,
just really impactful in a lot of
different ways. And then obviously like
that you get onto the field and a lot of
it's you I mean first it's the
selflessness of being going wherever we
we need him to go to help the team and
then two his talent and versatility to
go to. It's really hard to move from the
left to the right from inside to
outside. So uh you have to have a lot of
talent and just really a great work
ethic to be able to do that stuff. So,
um, couldn't be more impressed with him
as a person or a player and really
honored to be working with him.
>> All right. Thanks, AP.
>> All right. Thanks, guys.
>> Sorry, Jen.
>> Yeah.